http://youtu.be/wdOqQCNWC3c
khang_vgu
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: So let's look at the UART as part of the launch pad.
DR. JONATHAN: giờ ta xem UART, nó là 1 phần của launch pad
The launch pad has eight UARTs.
launch pad gồm 8 UARTs
The first one we'll look at is UART0 , which is here on PA1 and PA0.
cái đầu tiên là UART0, nó thuôc PA1 và PA0
PA1 is the transmitter as an output.
PA1 có vai trò là bộ phát, nó là output
PA0 is the receiver, which is an input.
PA0 là bộ thu, nó là input
This UART is hardwired into the debugger chips on your launch pad,
UART này thì được nối cứng vào chip debugger trên launch pad
goes across the USB cable to your PC, and shows up as a COM port.
nối tiếp với dây USB vào PC, như là 1 port COM
The second scenario, what we will see is UART1
UART thứ 2 là UART1
could be connected to PC5 and PC4.
nó sẽ kết nối với PC5 và PC4
This is the transmitter, and in this case,
đây là bộ phát, và trong trường hợp này, nó sẽ kết nối với launch pad thứ 2
we could connect to a second launch pad.
...
And we'll tie PC5 to PC4, and data will flow in this direction.
ta sẽ kết nối PC5 này vào PC4 trên launch pad, và data sẽ chạy theo hướng này
And we'll tie PC5 back to PC4.
trên launch pad, nối ngược PC5 lại vào PC4
And over here, it's the receiver, and over there it's the transmitter.
và đây là bộ thu, đây là bộ phát
So the roles are reversed.
ta thấy vai trò đã bị đảo ngược
And in order to make this work, as you know, we define voltage
để nó hoạt động, ta phải xác định Voltage giữa 2 đầu pin này
as the potential difference between two pins,
...
so whenever we use the UART protocol, we're
mỗi khi ta sử dụng UART protocol, ta phải kết nối hết vào GND
going to have to tie the grounds together.
...
We have one more possibility.
ta còn UART2
If we used UART2 with PD7 and PD6, and we wanted to connect to an external
nếu ta xài UART2 với PD7 và PD6, và ta muốn kết nối vào thiết bị ngoại vi ở khoảng cách xa
device very far away, we could take the transmitter and connect it to a driver
ta có thể lấy bộ thu -> kết nối vào chip driver - Maxim3232
chip called a Maxim3232 .
...
And this would allow, again three wires, transmit, receive, and ground.
và nó sẽ cho 3 phép, 3 dây: truyền - thu - GND
But this driver chip would allow us to go up to 50 feet.
chip driver này cho phép ta kết nối khoảng cách tới 50 feet
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: Using some sort of a cable?
DR. YERRABALLI: xài dây cáp hả?
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: Yes, a cable to an external device that's very far away.
DR. JONATHAN : yes, cáp nối tới thiết bị ngoại vi ở khoảng cách rất xa
And there's our receiver and our ground is tied together.
đây là bộ thu và đây là GND
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: So the DB9 connector,
DR. YERRABALLI: với bộ kết nối DB9 (hình này)
which you are very familiar with if you've used old machines,
nếu ta đã xài thiết bị cũ, thì ta sẽ thân thuộc với bộ kết nối xài serial port
is one such connector that uses the serial port.
....
It has nine pins on it, but only three of the pins
nó có 9 pin, nhưng chỉ có 3 cái là cần thiết
are essential, pin three, two, and five, and those make up
pin 3,2 và 5
the transmitter, receiver, and common ground.
the transmitter, receiver, and common ground.